A Finding Aid to the Louise Nevelson Papers, circa 1903-1988, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Correspondence, 1931-1984; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; (Boxes 1-2, 31-35, Sol 42; 6 linear feet)
  Hirschhorn, Joseph: 1968
  Hobart and William Smith Colleges: 1971
  Indiana, Robert: 1966
  Jackson, Martha (See Martha Jackson Gallery)
  Jacobi, Lotte: 1960, 1963, 1965
  Kendall, Tom: 1959, 1961, undated
  Knox, Seymour: 1968
  Kramer, Hilton: 1957
  Lipman, Howard: 1962
  Lipton, Seymour: 1955
  Mademoiselle: 1961, 1962
  Martha Jackson Gallery: 1956, 1959, 1960, 1961, 1962, 1967, 1968, undated
  Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Center for Advanced Visual Studies: 1971
  Miller, Kenneth Hayes: 1931, 1933
  Milone, Joe: 1941
  Minneapolios College of Art and Design: 1971
  Mount Holyoke College: 1962, 1964
  Museum of Art, Carnegie Institution: 1967, 1971, 1974
  Museum of Fine Arts of Houston: 1954
  Museum of Modern Art: 1943, 1953, 1955, 1964, 1967, 1968
  National Association of Women Artists: 1953, 1954
  National Foundation on the Arts and Humanities: 1966
  Neumann, Hans: 1962
  Neumann, J. B.: 1954
  New School for Social Research: 1961
  The New York Times: 1968
  New York State Council on the Arts: 1968
  The New Yorker: 1967
  Newsweek: 1967
  Nierenforf, Karl: 1941, 1943, 1946
  Nordjyllands Kunstmuseum: 1973
  Ono, Yoko: 1971
  Pace Gallery: 1976
  Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts: 1952, 1970
  Philadelphia College of Art: 1961, 1968
  Philadelphia Museum of Art: 1965
  Princeton University: 1962
  Queens College: 1958
  Rhode Island School of Design: 1971
  Riverside Museum: 1964
  Rockefeller, Nelson: 1960, 1962, 1966, 1968
  Roberts, Collette: 1952, 1953
  Robus, Hugo: 1958
  Rosenblum, Robert: 1958
  Sewall, Mrs. Sumner: 1943
  Silvermine Guild of Artists: 1953, 1954, 1955
  Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture: 1970, 1971
  Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum: 1964, 1966
  Tamarind Lithography Work Shop: 1971
  Tate Gallery: 1963, 1966, 1967, 1968
  Teachers College, Columbia University: 1964
  Trenton State College: 1961
  Tyler, Parker: 1958
  United States Committee of the International Association of Art: 1971
  University of Alabama, Department of Art: 1964
  University of Bridgeport: 1971
  University of Nebraska Art Galleries: 1951
  Vogue: 1964
  Wadsworth Atheneum Museum of Art: 1962
  Walker Art Center: 1971, 1973
  Weber, Max: 1947, 1948, 1950, 1951
  Western College for Women: 1964
  The White House: 1974
  Whitney Museum of American Art: 1950, 1956, 1957, 1962, 1964, 1966, 1967
  Wichita State University: 1974
  The Woman's College of The University of North Carolina: 1951
  Women's Interart Center: 1973
  Yale University, Department of Art: 1961
  - General Correspondence, Archival Resource Key (Box 1)
    - General Correspondence, 1931-1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - General Correspondence, 1941-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - General Correspondence, 1950-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - General Correspondence, 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - General Correspondence, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - General Correspondence, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - General Correspondence, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - General Correspondence, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - General Correspondence, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - General Correspondence, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - General Correspondence, 1961; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 36-37)
    - General Correspondence, 1962; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 38-40)
    - General Correspondence, 1963; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 41-42)
    - General Correspondence, 1964; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 43-44)
    - General Correspondence, 1965; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 45-46)
    - General Correspondence, 1966; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 47-48)
    - General Correspondence, 1967; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
    - General Correspondence, 1968; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
    - General Correspondence, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - General Correspondence, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - General Correspondence, 1971; Archival Resource Key; (5 folders) (Box 2, Folder 7-11)
    - General Correspondence, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - General Correspondence, 1973; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
    - General Correspondence, 1974; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 15-16)
    - General Correspondence, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - General Correspondence, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - General Correspondence, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - General Correspondence, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - General Correspondence, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - General Correspondence, undated; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 22-23)
  - Mike Nevelson Letters, Archival Resource Key (Box 2)
    - Letters, 1931-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 24-26)
    - Letters, 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Letters, 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Letters, 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Letters, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Letters, 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Letters, 1947-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Letters, 1950-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Letters, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Letters, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Letters, 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Letters, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Letters, 1956-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Letters, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Letters, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Letters, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Letters, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Letters, 1962-1965, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Nevelson Correspondence from Farnsworth Art Museum, Archival Resource Key
    - Farnsworth Art Museum Item-Level Inventory, 2002-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1957-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 31, Folder 4-18)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1979-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 1-17)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1983-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 1-4)
    - Business Correspondence, 1959-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 5-15)
    - Business Correspondence, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - Business Correspondence, 1979-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 1-5)
    - Business Correspondence, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Business Correspondence, 1980-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 7-15)
    - Business Correspondence, 1982-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 35, Folder 1-5)
    - Business Correspondence, 1973, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Mixed Personal and Business Correspondence, 1950s-1980s, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 35, Folder 7)
- Subject Files, 1955-1988; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; (Box 3, 35-36; 1.7 linear feet)
  Series consists of files of clippings, newsletters, correspondence, notes, announcements, programs, receipts, loan agreements and receipts, and other material, organized according to subject (name of organization or person, place, activity, format). Files relate to Nevelson's activities with various professional and arts-related organizations (such as Artists Equity Association); her participation in various workshops, panels, and conferences (including Meet the Artists course at New York University and the Tamarind Lithography Workshop); the exhibition of her work in other countries, and in museums and galleries, such as The Museum of Modern Art and Wadsworth Atheneum; the handling of certain business matters (including dealings with the gallery owner, Daniel Cordier, restoration of the Nevelson sculpture owned by Nelson Rockefeller that was damaged by fire, and various photograph orders), usually conducted by Nevelson's assistant, Tom Kendall, on her behalf. Files of biographical information and notes also relate to some of Nevelson's activities in publicizing her art work.
  Arrangement note
  It is not clear whether the subject organization of the files originates with Nevelson (or one her associates) or with Archives staff. The existing organization has for the most part been maintained. Files are arranged alphabetically. Related material can be found amongst the business records and printed material. While most of this material has been scanned, duplicates, some printed material, and the Farnsworth Art Museum addition has not.
  - Amarillo (Texas), 1962, 1964; Archival Resource Key; (Not scanned in entirety) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - American Abstract Artists, 1959-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - The American Federation of the Arts, 1962-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Art and the Community Institute, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - The Art Gallery (Directories), 1958-1962; Archival Resource Key; (Not scanned in entirety) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Art Students League, 1955-1960, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Artists Equity Association, 1957-1967; Archival Resource Key; (5 folders; not scanned in entirety) (Box 3, Folder 5-9)
  - Artists Equity Association, Address Book; Financial Information, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Arts Festival (Williamsport, Pennsylvania), 1968-1970; Archival Resource Key; (Not scanned in entirety) (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Auctions, 1958, 1961; Archival Resource Key; (Not scanned in entirety) (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Benson Gallery, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Bibliography, Pace Gallery and Others, circa 1970, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Bills, Orders, and Receipts, 1962-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Biographical Information (Publicity), 1959-1960; Archival Resource Key; (Not scanned in entirety) (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Brooklyn Museum, undated; Archival Resource Key; (Not scanned in entirety) (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - The Club, 1958-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Conference on World Affairs, 1964; Archival Resource Key; (Not scanned in entirety) (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Corber Designs, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Cordier, Daniel, 1959-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Cordier, Daniel, 1960-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Eilshemius, 1960-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Exhibitions, Caracas (Venezuela), 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Exhibitions, Germany, 1961-1962; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 21-22)
  - Exhibitions, Argentina, 1962-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Exhibitions, Los Angeles, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Farnsworth Library and Art Museum, Louise Nevelson and Nathan Berliawsky Archives, 1977-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 35, Folder 14-15)
  - Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors, 1961-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Foshee, Rufus, 1961-1969, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - Foshee, Rufus, Printed Material, 1959-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 35, Folder 17-18)
  - Four O'Clock Forums, 1953-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Galerie Alfred Schmela, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 35, Folder 19)
  - Galerie Jeanne Bucher, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Galleries, Various, 1962-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Great Neck Public Schools, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Hampden, Maine, School Project, circa 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 35, Folder 20)
  - Lane, Alvin, 1963-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 35, Folder 21)
  - Legal, Elliot J. Sachs and Galleries, 1961-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 35, Folder 22)
  - Legal, Harris B. Steinberg, 1963-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 35, Folder 23)
  - Legal, Sidney Janis and Pace Gallery, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Louise Nevelson Laboratory for Cancer Immunobiology, circa 1980-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Millicent Rogers Museum, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 1959-1964; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 30-32)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1959, 1962-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - National Association of Women Artists, 1959-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - National Association of Women Artists, 1963, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Nevelson, Mike, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Nevelson Plaza, New York City, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - New York Historical Society, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - New York University, "The Tropical Gardens", 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - New York Society of Women Artists, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - New York State Art Teachers Association, 1958; Archival Resource Key; (Not scanned in entirety) (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - New York University, 1958, 1961; Archival Resource Key; (Not scanned in entirety) (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Notes on (Nevelson) Art Work and Bibliography, 1960-1961; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 39-40)
  - Notes, Memos, and Correspondence (Tom Kendall), 1960-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Opera Theatre of St. Louis, circa 1983-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 8-9)
  - Opera Theatre of St. Louis, In Search of Orfeo, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Opera Theatre of St. Louis, In Search of Orfeo, Shirt, circa 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Photograph Orders, 1959-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Princeton University Conference, 1977-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Queens College, 1958-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Reviews, circa 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Richard J. Daley Memorial, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Riverside Museum, 1956-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Rockefeller Sculpture, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Scotsdale (Arizona), 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Sculptor's Guild, 1956-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Sculptor's Guild, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Skowhegan School of Paintings and Sculpture, 1970s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Storm King Art Center, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Tamarind Lithography Workshop, 1963; Archival Resource Key; (Not scanned in entirety) (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Tamarind Lithography Workshop, 1967-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - Titles, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Wadsworth Atheneum, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - "Wall for Jerusalem", 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 17)
  - Westbrook College Museum, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - World's Fair, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 19)
- Business Records, 1946-1981; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; (Boxes 3-5, 36-38, Sol 42; 3.8 linear feet)
  Series consists of files stemming from Nevelson's business dealings with the Martha Jackson Gallery (her primary representative from 1958 to 1962) and other business matters, usually carried out by her assistant, Tom Kendall, on her behalf; scattered note cards and drawings kept by Nevelson, documenting certain early works and their disposition; and checks, accounting books, as well as loose financial papers. Files include consignment receipts, statements, memos, correspondence, notes, inventories, disposition cards, notebooks, lists, and dummy pages for a Nevelson book (compiled from the text of an interview by Tal Streeter and photographs of Nevelson) that was never completed.
  The bulk of the files seem to relate to the large project of inventorying Nevelson's art work, including black wood constructions, white works, bronzes, etchings, and drawings, which was most likely carried out by Nevelson's assistant and gallery staff sometime in the early-1960s. Some inventories provide basic information about art works (including title, dates, dimensions, and so on). More detailed inventories, along with the lists, disposition cards, and notebooks which seem to have been used in compiling them, provide further information about the previous and/or current location, ownership, and disposition of art works. Some photographs and sketches of art work can be found on the disposition cards. Other files relate to the pricing, sale, and exhibition of Nevelson's art work.
  Files are divided between the 1966-1979 and 2018 Farnsworth Art Museum acquisitions, and are arranged in rough chronological order. Related material can be found amongst the subject files. Files from the 1966-1979 acquisition were scanned in its entirety.
  - Note Cards on Disposition of Certain Works (kept by Nevelson), 1946-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Drawings of Terra Cotta Sculptures, 1948-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Martha Jackson Gallery, 1958-1962; Archival Resource Key; (4 folders) (Box 3, Folder 55-58)
  - Inventory of Works, 1958-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Nevelson Inventory (Inventory of Nevelson Works in Martha Jackson Gallery), 1958-1960; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 60-62)
  - Detailed Inventory of Works, 1960s; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 63-64)
  - Detailed Inventory of Works, Lists and Disposition Cards, 1960s; Archival Resource Key; (9 folders) (Box 4, Folder 1-9)
  - Disposition Cards, 1960s; Archival Resource Key; (12 folders) (Box 4, Folder 10-21)
  - Disposition Cards, 1960s; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
  - Notebook, 1959-1960; Archival Resource Key; (7 folders) (Box 5, Folder 3-9)
  - Notebook, Etchings and Drawings, 1959-1961; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 10-11)
  - Notebook, Location or Ownership of Nevelson Sculptures as known to Tom Kendall, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Work File of Tom Kendall, 1959-1961; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 13-15)
  - Unfinished Nevelson Book, 1960; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 16-17)
  - Prices, 1960-1961; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 18-19)
  - Miscellaneous, 1961-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Itemized List for Martha Jackson Gallery Re: Extra Work on Bronze Sculptures, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Exhibition List and Notes, 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Lists, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Blank Consignment Receipts (Martha Jackson Gallery), undated; Archival Resource Key; (Not scanned) (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Business Records from Farnsworth Art Museum, 1948-1981; Archival Resource Key
    - Miscellaneous Papers, circa 1948-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 20)
    - Martha Jackson Gallery, Papers, 1950s-1960s, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 21)
    - Martha Jackson Gallery, Daniel Cordier, 1960-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 22)
    - Martha Jackson Gallery, Sculpture Casting in Turin, Italy, 1960-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 23)
    - Martha Jackson Gallery, Baden-Baden Exhibition, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 24)
    - Martha Jackson Gallery, Ledger and Inventory, 1961-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 25)
    - Martha Jackson Gallery, Pace Gallery, 1961-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 26)
    - Martha Jackson Gallery, Photographs and Printed Material, 1960s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 27)
    - Checkbooks, 1950-1959, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 28-32)
    - Checks, 1950-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 37, Folder 1-7)
    - Bank Slips, circa 1950-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Grand Central Moderns, 1954-1960, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Stuttman Gallery, 1957-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Sales and Installations, 1957-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Louise Nevelson's Representatives, 1959-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - Account Books, 1960-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 37, Folder 13-17)
    - Account Books, 1960-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 1-4)
    - Ledger, circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Pace Gallery, 1960-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 6-7)
    - Museum of Modern Art, Exhibition Department, 1962-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Nevelson Works; Sale of Louise Nevelson Eilshemius Paintings to Balin-Traube Gallery, circa 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Gifts, Brooklyn Museum, 1964-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Gifts, Archives of American Art, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Gifts, Museum of Modern Art and Whitney Museum, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - C. & C. Custom Woodworking, Receipts and Diagrams, 1968-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Sent to Pace Gallery Regarding Sculpture in Rockland, Maine, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 42, Folder 3)
- Writings, circa 1936-1980; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; (Box 5, 38, Sol 42; 0.5 linear feet)
  Series consists of writings by Nevelson, which shed light on different aspects of her creativity and on her ideas about art in general and her work in particular. Included are a journal of sorts in which she recorded her dreams for a two-month time period (from April 21 to June 21) in 1936; various poems and fragments of writings; various writings on art, including technical notes and sketches, titled pieces such as "The Birth of Painting (Picture Happy)" and "The Winged City," drafts of speeches on the artist Rose Newman-Wolinska and on sculpture, an article on sculpture for the Christian Science Monitor; statements which seem to have been written for The Whitney Review (1961-1962); salutes to others, including a poem for Dorothy Dehner which appeared in an exhibition catalog for one of her shows and the draft of a short piece (possibly a speech) in honor of Merce Cunningham; and drafts and galley proofs of Dawns and Dusks: Taped Conversations with Daiana MacKown by Louise Nevelson and Diana MacKown (1976).
  Writings are arranged in rough chronological order. A portion of this series has been scanned.
  - Dream Journal, 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Poems and Fragments, 1950s-1973; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 26-28)
  - Writings on Art, 1953-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 29)